

I'm a software engineer with 9 years of experience in analysis, design, development, testing and deployment of requirements; I have been a Support and Development Team Leader, planning and managing activities and persons in IT projects for Public Services and Telecommunications Companies; I have been working with scrum, Azure DevOps and git.

I'm responsible, respectful, analytical, creative, self-learning and I am be able to work in collaborative teams.

DAVID AUGUSTO HURTADO PIPICANO

Phone:

+57 3183706648

E-Mail:

dahurtadop@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dahurtadop/

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Collaborative Working
- Complex problem solver
- Agile Development
- Service-focused
- Self-Learning
- Test case design
- Testing execution
- Functional testing

Languages

Spanish – Native English – B1

Experience

01/2020 to Current Date

Software Engineering Specialist - MVM, Medellín, Colombia

- Analyze requirements, focused on the business support system from customers of Public Service and Telecommunications.
- Design, execute and document the test case of requirements.
- Diagnosticate, fix and solve errors occurred on the customer's system.
- Deliveries and Deployments requirements with Git and Azure DevOps.

03/2019 to 12/2019

Development Engineer - Axede, Cali, Colombia

- Analyze, design, develop and test requirements from customers in OSF system.
- Design and execute test case of requirements.
- Diagnosticate, fix and solve errors occurred on OSF system.
- Build APIs and Integrate TOA Oracle System with OSF system version 7.08.

10/2016 to 03/2019

OSF Consultant Engineer - Optima Consulting, Cali, Colombia

- Coordinate the Support and Development Team for monitoring and delivering tasks and activities to customers.
- Analyze, design, develop, test and deploy requirements about Public Service and Telecommunications Industries in OSF versions 7.07 and 7.08.

02/2016 to 10/2016

Development Engineer - Arquitecsoft, Cali, Colombia

- Analyze, design, develop, test and deploy requirements about Public Service and Telecommunications Industries in OSF versions 7.07.
- Diagnosticate, fix and solve errors in applications from Open Smartflex in versions 7.07.

02/2012 to 02/2016

Development Engineer - Open Systems International, Cali, Colombia

- Analyze, design, develop, test and deploy requirements about Public Service and Telecommunications Industries in Open Smartflex versions 7.07 and 7.08.
- Diagnosticate, fix and solve errors occurred on baseline of OSF systems in versions 7.07 and 7.08.

Education

2005-2015

Systems Engineer: Universidad del Cauca, Popayán, Colombia

Certifications

- DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate CertiProf
- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate CertiProf
- Diplomado en Gerencia de Proyectos PMI Universidad ICESI
- Planeación, Diseño y Ejecución de Pruebas de Software Green SQA
- Arquitectura Empresarial (OSF) Open Systems International
- Modelo de Procesos (OSF) Open Systems International
- Tuning SQL (OSF) Open Systems International
- Fundamentals v7.08 (OSF) Open Systems International
- Modelos de Negocio (Energía, Agua y Gas) v7.08 (OSF) Open Systems International